Finding Aid for the Collection of Material about the Spanish Civil War LSC.0205
UCLA Library Special Collections
A collection of material about the Spanish Civil War
1936-1939
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0205
1.0 Linear Feet (2 boxes and 1 oversize box)
Collection includes pamphlets, magazines, newspapers, a book, mailers, a typed manuscript, and broadsides relating to the Spanish Civil War, primarily covering Pro-Communist and Democratic materials.
2 boxes (1.0 linear ft.) and 1 oversize box
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942327943606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of pamphlets, magazines, newspapers, a book, mailers, a typed manuscript, and broadsides relating to the Spanish Civil War, published in the United States, England, France and Spain. Includes materials from the Spanish Refugee Aid, Inc., Pro-Fascist literature, and pro-Communist and Democratic literature. Includes work by Louis Fischer, Arnold Lunn, William Montevon, Earl Browder, Hubert C. Herring, Juan P. Fábregas and Fernando de los Rios.
Related Material
Del Amo Foundation Spanish Civil War Collection (Collection 2012). Available at the Department of Special Collections, Charles Young Research Library.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Archives.
- Spanish Refugee Aid Pamphlets, donation request, ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Pro-fascist literature Pamphlets, ca. 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Pro-Communist, Democratic and non-Interventionist literature Pamphlets, typed drafts, ca. 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Pro-Communist and Democratic literature Pamphlets, ca. 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Pro-Communist and Democratic literature Pamphlets, ca. 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Pro-Communist and Democratic literature, , ca. 1937 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Pamphlet and copy of From the Spanish Trenches, a collection of letters from Loyalists in Spain, edited by Marcel Acier
- Pro-Communist and Democratic literature Pamphlets and leaflet, ca. 1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Pro-Communist and Democratic literature Pamphlets, leaflets, magazine and bulletin, ca. 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Sunday Worker (New York), 25 April 1937 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Cronica (Madrid), 4 April 1937 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Photo History Magazine vol. 1, no. 1, April 1937 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Socorro Rojo Internacional. Está donde precisa. Poster for the International Red Aid (Socorro Rojo Internacional), undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
- undated (Box 3, Folder 5)